Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Records on Microfilm 5976 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Records on Microfilm
1940-1977
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters
5976 mf
3.33 cubic feet
30 microfilm reels
Records.
This is Series A, Part 1 of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters records.
5743747
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 12, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 05, 2015
Biographical / Historical
The Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters (BSCP) was, in 1925, the first labor organization led by blacks to receive a charter in the American Federation of Labor (AFL). It merged in 1978 with the Brotherhood of Railway and Airline Clerks (BRAC), now known as the Transportation Communications International Union.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5462 mf: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters, Chicago Division, Selected Papers on Microfilm 6110 mf: Records of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters, Series A, Parts 1-3 on Microfilm
Railroads -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Porters -- Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; African Americans -- Employment -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters.; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters. Lady Auxiliary
5743747
- Correspondence 1925-1927 (Reel 1)
  - 0001. 1925. 132 pages., 1 (Reel 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Major Topics: Pullman Company operations and activities; tipping of porters; Pullman stock purchase plan for employees; C and W Railway schedule of wages and rules of compensation of conductors and trainmen; applications and dues; correspondence.
  - 0133. January-April 1926. 142 pages., 2 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: Assigned working numbers for porters; financial statements; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; effort to eradicate Communist influence in trade unions; voting plan in Omaha District; applications and dues; embezzlement scandal; revision of schedule of rules and rates of pay for Canadian railroads.
  - 0275. May-July 1926. 106 pages., 3 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: Organization meetings; financial statements; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organization activities; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; dispensation for new members; dues collection; Watson-Parker Bill; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People endorsement of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters.
  - 0381. August 1926. 122 pages., 4 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: Correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; Pullman employee representation plan; organization meetings; Randolph wins libel suit against the Whip; porter grievances; financial statements; dues collection; Randolph's meeting with Clarence Darrow; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters legal expenses to Chandler Owen; questionnaires; organization meetings; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary membership drive; request for conference with Pullman; applications; attack on the Pullman Porters Benevolent Association; propaganda circulars; confiscation of employee property by Pullman; negotiations with Pullman; appointment of a National Advisory Committee of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters.
  - 0503. September-October 1926. 155 pages., 5 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: Applications; Pullman employee representation plan; dues collection; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; questionnaires; organization meetings; porter grievances; request for conference with Pullman; suggestions on wage scale and working conditions; financial statements; reduction in membership; request for conference with Pullman; Brotherhood of Railway Trainmen's assistance to the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case before National Mediation Board.
  - 0658. November-December 1926. 166 pages., 6 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: Pullman intimidation of porters in employee representation plan elections; Chicago Enquirer's support for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; questionnaires; porter grievances; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; demands relating to wages, rules, and working conditions; financial statements; propaganda; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters hearing before the National Mediation Board; organization meetings; Pullman Porters Benevolent Association convention; applications; standing of the Pullman Porters Benevolent Association under the Railway Labor Act; financial statements; dues collection; expenses.
  - 0824. January 1927. 78 pages., 7 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters opposition to communism; special assessment; Pullman reprisals against employees; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; organization meetings; financial statements; National Mediation Board proceedings in Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case.
  - 0902. February 1927. 83 pages., 8 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: Propaganda; special assessment; dues collection; financial statements; changes in Pullman employee representation plan; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; membership statistics; organization meetings; National Mediation Board proceedings in the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case; tipping issue; National Mediation Board union representation election for Pullman porters.
- Correspondence 1927 (Reel 2)
  - 0001. March-April 1927. 116 pages., 1 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; porter grievances; questionnaires; Pullman employee representation plan; special assessment; financial statements; dues collection; propaganda; National Mediation Board proceedings in Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case; political situation in Chicago; reports on poor working conditions; New York Citizens Committee of One Hundred; funds advanced to discharged members; Randolph's speech to the National Urban League Conference; resignation of Ella Jones; president of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary; activities of Pullman Company spies; support of Negro ministers for the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; aims of the Trade Union Committee for Organizing Negro Workers.
  - 0117. May 1927. 58 pages., 2 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Dues collection; National Mediation Board proceedings in Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; Wage Board proceedings; financial statements; Pullman reprisals against Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organizers; Pullman employee representation plan; special assessment.
  - 0175. June 1927. 77 pages., 3 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Dues collection; special assessment; financial statements; Pullman reprisals against Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organizers; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; wages and working conditions of Negro porters; National Mediation Board proceedings in the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case; endorsement of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters by the Switchmen's Union of North America; list of new members.
  - 0252. July 1927. 56 pages., 4 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Dues collection; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; alleged National Mediation Board denial of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters request for wage increase; special assessment; National Mediation Board proceedings in the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case; Pullman propaganda; Pullman reprisals against Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organizers; financial statements.
  - 0308. August 1927. 67 pages., 5 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Applications; financial statements; special assessment; dues collection; list of telegrams sent by A. Philip Randolph; National Mediation Board proceedings in the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; wages and working conditions of Pullman porters.
  - 0375. September 1927. 85 pages., 6 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Pay rates for Pullman porters, attendants, and maids; applications; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; dues collection; special assessment; itinerary of tour by A. Philip Randolph and A.L. Totten; financial statements; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters files petition with Interstate Commerce Commission regarding Pullman case; wages and working conditions of Pullman Porters; Pullman propaganda; elections under Pullman employees representation plan.
  - 0460. October 1927. 77 pages., 7 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Dues collection; special assessment; fund-raising activities; Pullman reprisals against Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organizers; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; hearing of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case by Interstate Commerce Commission; financial statements; election under the Pullman employees representation plan; special assessments; list of members in the Chicago District; mass meeting; Pullman Company intimidation and propaganda.
  - 0537. November 1927. 95 pages., 8 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Applications; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case before the Interstate Commerce Commission; mass meeting; financial statements; special assessments; dues collection; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; Pullman Company intimidation; Pullman wage conference; organization meetings; Pullman Porters Benevolent Association convention
  - 0632. December 1927. 81 pages., 9 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Hearing of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case before the Interstate Commerce Commission; Negro Labor Conference; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; financial statements; special assessments; dues collection; Pullman wage conference; Pullman employees representation plan; support of Chicago Defender for the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; plan to charge fee or duplicate dues and membership cards; Pullman Company intimidation.
  - 0713. 1927. 84 pages., 10 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Mediation of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Pullman Dispute; instructions to Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organizers on handling strike situation; duties of Pullman porters; program of action for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organizers; Pullman employees representation plan; schedule of rules and pay rates for the Canadian National Railways; newspaper comments on Pullman porters wage and tip case; membership lists; porter grievances; organization meetings.
  - 0797. Membership Lists, 1927. 181 pages., 11 (Reel 2)
- Correspondence 1928-1930 (Reel 3)
  - 0001. January-February 1928. 147 pages., 1 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: Negro Labor Conference; financial statements; proceedings in Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case before the Interstate Commerce Commission; conference of Brotherhood chiefs; Pullman employees stock purchase plan; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; Pullman propaganda; dues collection; membership lists.
  - 0148. March-April 1928. 100 pages., 2 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: Correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; dues collection; conductors' wage increase; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case before the Interstate Commerce Commission; financial statements; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters strike vote; proposed resignation of Randolph to achieve Pullman agreement; mass meeting; propaganda.
  - 0248. May-June 1928. 97 pages., 3 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters strike vote; correspondence between a. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Policy Committee conference; financial statements; Pullman reprisals against Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organizers; propaganda; Pullman Company intimidation; amendment to the Railway Labor Act.
  - 0345. July-August 1928. 108 pages., 4 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: Financial statements; new Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters oath; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Policy Committee conference; Pullman Company intimidation; Pullman employees representation plan; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and Pullman propaganda; tipping issue; yellow dog contracts; Catholic Industrial Conference; endorsement of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters by the Negro Business League.
  - 0453. September-December 1928. 142 pages., 5 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: Catholic Industrial Conference; propaganda; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize Pullman porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters insurance plan; porter wages and working conditions; yellow dog contracts; elections under the Pullman employees representation plan; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to secure statements from Herbert Hoover and Alfred E. Smith; Pullman Company intimidation; charges of dishonest practices by Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organizers.
  - 0595. 1929. 154 pages., 6 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: Articles on the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Negro Labor Conference; relations between the Pullman Company and its porters; porters wages and working conditions; attack on A.L. Totten; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters membership in the American Federation of Labor; mass meeting; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters first annual convention.
  - 0749. January-October 1930. 109 pages., 7 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: Dues assessments; financial statements; porter grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters affiliation with the American Federation of Labor; United States Supreme Court outlaws company unions; Pullman employees representation plan; American Federation of Labor notes for speakers; injunction against Pullman Company; Pullman Company intimidation.
  - 0858. November-December 1930. 69 pages., 8 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: Financial statements; injunction against Pullman Company; election under the Pullman employees representation plan; Pullman propaganda; alleged diversion of funds by Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters officials; Negro Labor Conference; Illinois Labor Laws; American Federation of Labor notes for speakers.
- Correspondence 1931-1936 (Reel 4)
  - 0001. January-April 1931. 101 pages., 1 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Randolph's open letter to the Pullman Company; Negro Labor Conference; limitations on federal courts injunction power in labor disputes; American Federation of Labor notes for speakers; Pullman employees representation plan; Pullman Company spies; reinstatement of members; Reduction in forces and wages by Pullman; Illinois legislative program for labor; Kansas City mass meeting; Milton Webster's visit to West Coast.
  - 0102. May-June 1931. 56 pages., 2 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Milton Webster's visit to Minneapolis, St. Paul, and Kansas City; Illinois legislative program for labor; porter grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters recognized by Milwaukee Railroad Company; dues collection; economic plight of Negroes; Ohio passes bill outlawing yellow dog contracts; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to get injunction against Pullman under the Railway Labor Act.
  - 0158. July-December 1931. 158 pages., 3 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Ohio outlaws yellow dog contract; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters injunction against Pullman Company union; porter grievances; Milton Webster's visits to Kansas City and the West Coast; Pullman Company spies; porters demand for eight-hour workday; porter injury claims; articles by A. Philip Randolph; duties of porters; exploitation of Pullman porters; dues collection; election under Pullman employees representation plan; working conditions; The Crisis; tipping issue; American Federation of Labor notes for speakers; index of press reports and economic supplements of the International Federation of Trade Unions.
  - 0316. January-May 1932. 129 pages., 4 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Membership list; dues collection; limitations on federal courts injunction power in labor disputes; reduction of hours; wage decrease for Pullman porters; address by Randolph on the Negro worker in the depression; unemployment relief plan; bill for five-day workweek; tipping issue; Illinois state charter for Negro Employees Improvement Association; seniority rights; memorandum of agreement between the Southern Pacific and the Dining Car Cooks and Waiters Union; minutes of the Advisory Council on Race Relations of the Council of Christian Associations; allegations that Randolph was a Communist leader; Tom Mooney case in California.
  - 0445. June-December 1932. 117 pages., 5 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters injunction case against Pullman; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Fiorello LaGuardia; porter wage reductions; fund-raising activities; basic work month; Randolph's address on the Negro in the trade union movement; proposed establishment of a Labor Institute at the University of Illinois; Workers Education Bureau; dues collection; Pullman Company intimidation and propaganda.
  - 0562. January 1933-January 1935. 170 pages., 1933-1935; 6 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Unemployment relief; A. Philip Randolph's address to the American Federation of Labor convention; membership list; dues collection; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters injunction case against Pullman; fund-raising activities; Fiorello LaGuardia's address to the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters eighth anniversary celebration; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters educational activities; list of organizations affiliated with the American Federation of Labor; conference dealing with Negro workers in relation to National Recovery Administration code.
  - 0732. February-December 1935. 161 pages., 7 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Schedule of regulations for the Pennsylvania Railroad; discontinuance of retirements under Pullman pension plan; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organization campaign; Pullman union representation elections; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters application for American Federation of Labor international charter; dues collection; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters contribution to social progress; National Mediation Board certification of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters as official representative of Pullman porters.
  - 0893. 1936. 48 pages., 8 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Dues collection; business meetings of Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; brief for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters election ballot.
- Correspondence 1937-1940 (Reel 5)
  - 0001. January-December 1937. 125 pages., 1 (Reel 5)
    Major Topics: Dues collection; railroad retirement legislation; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Wagner Labor Relations Act; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago Midwest and Detroit Regional Zone Conference; instructions for determining work hours and wage rates of porters; major features of new Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman agreement.
  - 0126. 1937. 115 pages., 2 (Reel 5)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters strike ballot; lists of delinquent members; porters' service guidebook; program for re-employment, rehabilitation, and government ownership of the railways; dues collection.
  - 0241. January-September 23, 1938. 126 pages., 3 (Reel 5)
    Major Topics: Agreement between the Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul, and Pacific Railroad Company and the Dining Car Employees' Union; seniority lists; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; in charge service; porter grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters elections; instructions for organization committees; major features of new Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman agreement; American Federation of Labor unemployment report; constitution and general rules.
  - 0367. September 24-December 31, 1938. 156 pages., 4 (Reel 5)
    Major Topics: Report on Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters fifth national convention activities; program of the National Inter-racial Conference of Churchmen; porter pay rates and working conditions; delinquent members; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities.
  - 0523. 1939. 164 pages., 5 (Reel 5)
    Major Topics: Time slips; delinquent members; dues collection; union representation election for porters of the Chicago and Northwestern Railway Company; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Young Women's Christian Association Workers' Scholarship; National Conference of Negro Railroad Workers; agreement governing pay rates and working conditions between the Railway Train Porters, Local Number 20672, American Federation of Labor and the Illinois Central Yazoo and Mississippi Valley and Gulf and Ship Island Railroad Companies; seniority assignments; rules and pay rates for the Chicago, Burlington, and Quincy Railroad Company; proposed government ownership of railroads; organized labor's stake in World War II; porter rest periods; health hazards; porter grievances; report of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters New York Division Fact Finding Committee.
  - 0687. January-April 1940. 121 pages., 6 (Reel 5)
    Major Topics: Instructions for porters on the Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul, and Pacific Railroad Company; list of non-Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters members in the Pittsburgh Division; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Ohio State Conference on Employment Problems of the Negro; porter grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters labor conference in Jacksonville Division; minutes of the Keep America Out of War Congress; New York State Conference on Social Legislation; Pullman disciplinary hearing; dues collection; relief assignments.
  - 0808. May-September 1940. 105 pages., 7 (Reel 5)
    Major Topics: Articles by A. Philip Randolph; dispute between the Brotherhood of Railway and Steamship Clerks and the Railway Express Agency, Incorporated; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; benefits under the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act; North Western Porters Industrial Organization; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters convention in New York City; status of the Pullman Porters and Maids Protective Association; porter grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitution and general rules.
  - 0913. September 21-December 1940. 133 pages., 8 (Reel 5)